Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Local 82 records 1937-2003 IBT0036
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Local 82 records
1937-2003
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America
IBT0036
5 Linear Feet
This collections contains material produced by the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Local 82 dating from 1937-2003. The bulk of the material dates from 1940-1960. Included are a variety of materials related to the day-to-day operation of the Local, such as correspondence, meeting minutes, meeting notices and attendance lists, dues ledgers, contract agreements, seniority lists, membership applications,contract negotiation and agreements dating.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 2012 [2012.082].
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Administrative files and Contract Negotiation and Agreements
Scope and Contents
This collection contains records produced by the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Local 82. The material dates from 1937-2003 with the bulk of the material dated 1940-1960. Included are a variety of materials related to the day-to-day operation of the Local, such as correspondence, meeting minutes, meeting notices and attendance lists, dues ledgers, contract agreements, seniority lists and membership applications. Also included are contract negotiation and agreements dating from 1939-1981. Of particular note are correspondence and other materials from the National War Labor Board, which was established by President Roosevelt in 1942.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Labor; Labor unions; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Contracts; World War, 1939-1945; Labor unions -- Boston -- History -- 20th century; United States. National War Labor Board (1942-1945)
- Administrative Files, 1937-2003; 1940-1960; Series 1; 3.5 Linear Feet
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains IBT Local 82 Administrative Files dating from 1937-2003. The bulk of the material dates from 1940-1960. Included are a variety of materials related to the day-to-day operation of the Local, such as correspondence, meeting minutes, meeting notices and attendance lists, dues ledgers, contract agreements, seniority lists, event anouncements, membership applications, newspaper clippings and other miscellaneous items.
  - Acme Truck Service, 1955-1957; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Boston Truck Company, 1991-2003; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Cambridge Central Labor Union, 1952-1958; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Central Labor Union of Boston and Vicinity, 1953-1958; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Columbia Warehouse Storage Company, 1955-1958; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Letters from Members [1/2], 1946-1948; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Letters from Members [2/2], 1949-1953; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Leters to Members [1/2], 1947-1951; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Letters to Members [2/2], 1951-1953; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: National Union [1/2], 1952-1956; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: National Union [2/2], 1953-1957; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1937-1945; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1946-1991; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Gilchrist Company, 1951-1973; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - H. Goldman, Inc. [1/2], 1950-1959; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - H. Goldman, Inc. [2/2], 1959; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - IBT Labor-Management Joint Committee Meeting Minutes, 1942 December 15-16; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - IBT National Rubber Committee Meeting Minutes, 1943 January - September; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - IBT National Rubber Committee Meeting Minutes, 1943 November - 1944 March; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - IBT Permanent Committee Meeting Minutes, 1942 March-May; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - J.A. Garvey Transportation, Inc. [1/3], 1951-1955; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - J.A. Garvey Transportation, Inc. [2/3], 1954-1959; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - J.A. Garvey Transportation, Inc. [3/3], 1953-1959; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Jackson Chairs, Inc., 1953-1958; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Jordan Marsh Company, 1941-1943; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Jordan Marsh Company, 1943-1945; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Jordan Marsh Company, 1945-1946; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Jordan Marsh Company, 1946-1950; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Jordan Marsh Company, 1951-1953; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Jordan Marsh Company, 1969; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Jordan Marsh Company Seniority Lists, 1948-1952; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Jordan Marsh Company Seniority Lists, 1953-1956; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Jordan Marsh Company Seniority Lists, 1953-1958; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Kane's, Inc., 1943-1945; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Kane's, Inc., 1943-1951; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Kane's, Inc., 1944-1956; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Lincoln Oil Company, 1948-1951; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Local Unions, 1952-1955; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - M & A Trucking Company, 1952-1956; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Massachusetts State Federation of Labor, 1943-1945; Series 1 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Meeting Attendance and Dues Lists, 1952-1958; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Notices, 1946-1955; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Membership Applications, 1957; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - National War Labor Board, 1938-1948; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - National Warehouse Division, 1952-1957; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - National Warehouse Division, 1954-1960; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1940s; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Union Label and Services Trades Department, 1953-1956; Series 1 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous [1/6], 1940-1945; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous [2/6], 1943-1958; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous [3/6], 1947-1952; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous [4/6], 1940-1957; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous [5/6], 1946-1960; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous [6/6], 1948-1977; Series 1 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Contract Negotiation and Agreements, 1939-1981; Series 2; 1.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains materials related to IBT Local 82 contract negotiation and agreements dating from 1939-1981. Included are agreement texts, meeting minutes, reports, correspondence and handwritten notes. Of particular note are correspondence and other materials from the National War Labor Board, which was reestablished by President Roosevelt in 1942.
  - Floral City Furniture Company, 1965; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Gilchrist Company [1/2], 1946-1949; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Gilchrist Company [2/2], 1940-1950; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hassol's, Inc., 1965; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - John H. Pray and Sons Company, 1946-1949; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Joint Council No. 10, 1943-1947; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Jordan Marsh Company, 1940-1948; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Jordan Marsh Company, 1941; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jordan Marsh Company, 1941-1946; Series 2 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Jordan Marsh Company, 1942-1945; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Jordan Marsh Company, 1942-1955; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Jordan Marsh Company, 1944; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Jordan Marsh Company, 1946-1948; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Jordan Marsh Company, 1964-1966; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Kane's, Inc., 1945-1950; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - M.J. Freed, Inc., 1966; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - O'Hearns Moving Service, Inc., 1979-1981; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Paine's of Boston, Inc., 1948-1951; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Royal Furniture Company, Inc., 1966; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Welch Motor Lines, 1940-1954; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous [1/3], 1939-1949; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous [2/3], 1948-1950; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous [3/3], 1941-1948; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)